Guide to the Morris Albert Copeland Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Morris Albert Copeland Papers
1912-1984.
Copeland, Morris Albert, 1895-
ca. 2,500 items (16 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
MS#0280
4078649
This collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, notes, documents, photographs, and printed materials of Copeland
Biographical Note
Economist, professor of economics at Cornell University, visiting professor at Columbia University during 1954. Copeland developed the idea of Flow-of-funds Accounts, was an expert on the coordination of government statistics, and was the author of numerous books and journal articles.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, notes, documents, photographs, and printed materials of Copeland, including his recent correspondence and subject files, and the manuscripts and printed copies of his articles and papers.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in five series:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Subject File
Series III: Manuscripts
Series IV: Printed Materials
Series V: 1984 Gift
Subjects
Columbia University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Economics--Study and teaching.; Economics--Research.; Photoprints.; Economists.; College teachers.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: Boxes 2-16. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1983 M-83 Copeland, Morris Albert Gift
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Cataloged correspondence (Box 1)
    - John Maurice Clark (Box 1)
    - Paul Howard Douglas (Box 1)
    - Irving Fisher (Box 1)
    - Milton Friedman (Box 1)
    - John Maynard Keynes (Box 1)
    - Alexander Meiklejohn (Box 1)
    - Frances Perkins (Box 1)
    - Edwin Robert Anderson Seligman (Box 1)
    - Frank William Taussig (Box 1)
  - Uncataloged correspondence
    - 1927-1977 (Box 1)
    - 1977-1983 (Box 2)
- Series II: Subject File
  - American Economic Association, 1957 meeting (Box 3)
  - Amherst College - Alumni, 1967-1979 (Box 3)
  - Banco Central de Venezuela, 1975-1978 (Box 3)
  - The Brookings Institution (The Robert Brookings Graduate School), 1924-1977 (Box 3)
  - The Central Statistical Board (Washington), 1933-1941 (Box 3)
  - "Concerning the origin of a money economy." by M.A.C., correspondence, 1971-7 (Box 4)
  - Copeland, Morris Albert
    - Biographical, 1968-1970 (Box 4)
    - Class record books, 1966-1969 (Box 4)
    - Medicare, 1971-1982 (Box 4)
    - Personal (Box 4)
    - Photographs, appointments, certificates, 1915-1966 (Box 4)
  - Cosmos Club (.Washington), 1976-1982 (Box 4)
  - Davenport, Herbert Joseph, 1929-1965 (Box 4)
  - Dooley, Peter C, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Douglas, Paul Howard - A.E.A. paper, 1947 (Box 4)
  - East-West Conferences, 1955-1960 (Box 4)
  - Employment - job vacancies, 1966-1971 (Box 4)
  - Fabricant, Solomon - paper, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Fordham University contract, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Garvy, George - paper (Box 5)
  - Gibbs, Julian Howard, 1979-1982 (Box 5)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Heckscher Grant - Cornell University, 1926-1927 (Box 5)
  - Income Conference (Conference on Research in Income and Wealth), 1970-1982 (Box 5)
  - Lissner, Will, 1971-1981 (Box 5)
  - The Macmillan Company, 1964-1978 (Box 5)
  - Meiklejohn, Alexander - Experimental College, 1923-1982 (Box 5)
  - Memorials, 1948-1978 (Box 5)
  - Millar, James Robert, 1965-1983 (Box 5)
  - Moneyflows (Flow of funds), 1947-1981 (Box 6-7)
  - Oyis, D.S., 1977 (Box 8)
  - Reed, Louis Schultz, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Salkever, Louis Romov, 1967-1969 (Box 8)
  - Schultz, Theodore William - paper, 1974 (Box 8)
  - U.N. - Wholesale prices (Box 8)
  - Uselding, Paul, 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Vantage Press, Inc., 1979-1981 (Box 8)
  - Venice Sands, Venice, Florida, 1973-1977 (Box 8)
- Series III: Manuscripts
  - by M.A. Copeland
    - Ph.D. thesis:Some phases of institutional value theory, University of Chicago, 1921 (Box 8)
    - Articles & papers, 1917-1980 (Box 9-10)
    - Notes on various subjects (Box 11)
- Series IV: Printed Materials
  - Articles & pamphlets by M.A. Copeland, 1919-1982 (Box 12-13)
  - Miscellaneous printed, 1912-1979 (Box 14)
- Series V: 1984 Gift
  - Amherst College & the Copeland Colloquium at Amherst (Box 15)
  - Awards (Box 16)
  - Copeland personal memorabilia (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1912-1985 (Box 16)
  - Manuscripts (Box 16)
  - Photographs (Box 16)
  - Printed materials (Box 16)
  - Smythe, Dallas W. (Box 16)
  - Spanish vocabulary (Box 16)